Register of the Komitety obshchestvennogo samoupravlenii͡a records
Hoover Institution Archives
Komitety obshchestvennogo samoupravlenii͡a records
1988-1998
93012
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes (2.1 linear feet)
Minutes, resolutions, reports, correspondence, and studies relating to the self-government movement in various cities and towns of Russia, and especially in Moscow.
Komitety obshchestvennogo samoupravlenii͡a.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Local self-governance as a public institution in Russia dates back to the nineteenth century. In Soviet times, however, local self-governance was transformed into a powerless branch of the State.
At the beginning of the 1990s with the restructuring of the economy, the local self-governance was declared to be an independent structure in the system of government. The new 1995 federal law "On the General Principles of Organization of Local Self Governance in the Russian Federation" provided new impulse to the establishment and development of local self-governance in Russia.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Komitety obshchestvennogo samoupravlenii͡a records consist of minutes, resolutions, reports, correspondence, studies, and clippings relating to the self-government movement in various cities and towns of Russia, and especially in Moscow.
These files are maintained in alphabetical order by city and town names as arranged by the organization.
Local government--Soviet Union.; Local government--Russia (Federation); Moscow (Russia)--Politics and government.; Soviet Union--Politics and government--1985-1991.; Russia (Federation)--Politics and government--1991-
- Arkhalgel'sk, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- Barnaul, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 3: 13)
- Berezniaki, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 4: 15)
- Birobidzhan, 1998 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Borovichi, 1997 (Box-folder 5: 6)
- Bratsk, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- Cheboksary, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Chita, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 3: 18)
- Ialta, 1990-1990 (Box-folder 3: 23)
- Iaroslavl', 1989-1997 (Box-folder 4: 2, Box-folder 5: 14)
- Ivanovo, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Kaluga, 1997 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Kemerovo, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- Kirov, 1997 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- Krasnodar, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 22)
- Krasnoiarsk, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Kurgan, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- Leninsk-Kuznetskii, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 17)
- Lipetsk, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 4: 17)
- Moscow, 1988-1997
  - General, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
  - Raionnye komitety, 1988-1991
    - Baumanskii, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Cheremushkinskii, 1988 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Dmitrovskii, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 4: 18)
    - Dzerzhinskii, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Frunzenskii, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Gagarinskii, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - Kalininskii, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - Khoroshevskii, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Kievskii, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 1: 11-13)
    - Kirovskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - Krasnogvardeiskii, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 1: 14-15, Box-folder 2: 19, Box-folder 3: 1-2)
    - Kuntsevskii, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Leningradskii, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Leninskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Moskvoretskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - Oktiabr'skii, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Perovskii, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 4-5)
    - Pervomaiskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - Sevastopol'skii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - Solntsevskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Sovetskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - Sverdlovskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - Taganskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - Timiriazevskii, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Tushinskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - Volgogradskii, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - Voroshilovskii, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - Zelenogradskii, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - Zheleznodorozhnyi, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 17)
- Murmansk, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Murom, 1998
- Nal'chik, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 4: 14)
- Nizhnii Novgorod, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 4: 20, Box-folder 5: 1)
- Novgorod, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 4: 6, Box-folder 5: 3)
- Novosibirsk, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Omsk, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 15)
- Penza, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Per'm, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- Pskov, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- Samara, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 5: 9-10)
- Saransk, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 12)
- Saratov, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 4: 16, Box-folder 5: 11)
- Sergiev Posad, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 12)
- Shakhty, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Sochi, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 21)
- Stavropol', 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 20)
- Sverdlovsk (Ekaterinburg), 1990 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Syzran', 1995-1998 (Box-folder 5: 7-8)
- Taganrog, 1991-1998 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- Tiumen', 1990-1992 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Tol'iatti, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Tver', 1998 (Box-folder 5: 13)
- Ulan-Ude, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 14)
- Vladimir, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Vologda, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 3: 19)
- Vorkuta, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Zlatoust, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 16)